MUNFFBUR RAHMAN.M

Senior Software Engineer

Summary

Exercise knowledge of IT concepts, strategies, and methodologies for over **6 years** in Web application and product development. Sound knowledge on web based application, utilizing web services, client-server techniques, architecture, design and development tools and technical standards.

Work Experience

Industry Portal – FedEx International

May 2018 to Present

Description: To create, manage and track Inbound shipments from EU Origin to serving worldwide.

Roles and responsibilities

- Designed front end architecture and carried out development activity under S.O.L.I.D principles.
- Developed shared utility services which are consumed by most of the components, hence avoiding duplication or repetition of code.
- Developed existing core business component in more advanced way, resulting more users adopting it, as the advance one is feasible (UX) and efficient.
- Involved in Code review, refactoring and deployment activities.

Accomplishments

 Received summit award for resuming application back from red zone to green and later released for production.

Dealer Management System - TVS

Oct 2017 to May 2018

Description: To manage, track all two wheeler related business operation throughout India, such as vehicle in stock, service and sales from dealers associated with company.

Roles and responsibilities

- Being a Full stack developer, analyzing business requirements and implementing it accordingly with adherence to industry standards.
- Developing generic validation service for complex validation and Implementing graphs and charts for better UX where required.
- Developed backend using Express.js (nodejs framework) with JWT authentication protocol for RESTful API's communication.

Accomplishments

 Refactored application resulted in, reduction of size to 60%, instant loading and non glitch operations throughout the application.

Slingshot – Merrill Corporation

Jun 2016 to Sep 2017

Description: Microsoft office add-on, used to manage, assign and track progress of users on shared word document content assigned by the document owner.

Roles and responsibilities

- Converted complex user interface to ease with minimum view port availability.
- Segregation of components into shared, child and generic, resulting in creation of fewer components and maintaining existing code base robust and modular
- Codes written in component are singleton in nature which is solely responsible for defined business operation, making scalable compliance

Contact

 \boxtimes muneeb.rahman.m@gmail.com

(+91 95667 47746

Employment

Mphasis Limited Bangalore

Senior Software

Engineer May 18 to Present

KasponTechworks

Pvt Ltd Chennai

Senior Software

Engineer Jul 15 to May 18

Qnex Technologies

LLP Chennai
Team Leader Mar 14 to Jun 15

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript and Typescript

Web Technologies

REST, HTML5, CSS3 and SCSS

Data Modelling

JSON, JSONP, XML and CSV

Libraries/APIs

HighCharts.js, sheet xlsx-js, jQuery, Angular Material, ng-bootstrap and Node.js.

Tools

GitLab, Postman, Jenkins and Visual Studio Code.

Paradigms

Agile, SAFe and Scrum

Platforms

Windows and Ubuntu

Frameworks

Bootstrap, Express.js, Ionic, Vue, Jasmine karma, Angular 2, 4 and AngularJs

Misc

User Experience (UX), Responsive Web Design (RWD)

Application Protocol

LDAP

Data Management

MySQL and MongoDB

MUNEEBUR RAHMAN.M

Senior Software Engineer

Vendor Training portal – UK

Feb 2016 to Jun 2016

Description: To promote, give training on handling latest desktop and laptop for vendor and sales men, post which they are capable to address customer.

Roles and responsibilities

- Solely developed algorithm for Quiz, based on product and vendor Location which prompts vendor to take quiz when new product is launched with catalogue handed over before taking quiz.
- Developed customized reports on vendor business operations, increasing in productivity and revenue for the organization.

Project Management System – TVS Credit

Jul 2015 to Jan 2016

Description: To create, monitor and track IT projects from different departments with respect to time and resource availability of developer.

Roles and responsibilities

- Defined components to enhancing the UX on dashboard by rendering various charts (pie, bar, column) for different departments. Application is more of monitoring in nature, resulting in more pictorial and less textual representation.
- Implemented Gantt and Column range charts to display actual ETA and current ETA of a given project and availability of resource.
- Exporting charts in different formats such as PDF, PNG and JPEG for user to download.

Accomplishments

• Created global Login module which consumed by other projects for both internal and external users.

Resource Management Portal – Telecom Sector

Sep 2014 to Jun 2015

Description: To create, track associate and automate mobile number screening on portal, to ease business operations.

- Developed algorithm based on mobile number which has not attended by any
 associate and assigning it to available associate. After completion of business
 operation, the request is flagged and forwarded for further process.
- Tracking associate details, like number of hour's clocked, customer attended and targets achieved out of target assigned and finally emailing their report sheet to managers.

Accomplishments

- Fetching automated mobile number instead of manual resulted in decrease of process time and increase in production.
- Automated report sheet of associate saved manager time in creating it manually which saved time and resource.

Dynamic and static websites

Mar 2014 to Aug 2014

- Working on multiple backend components independently.
- Created approximately 10 dynamic and static websites.
- Created ecommerce website for UK client from scratch and integrated to payment gateway.

Education

MCA – Master of computer application Veltech Multitech Dr Rangarajan Dr Sakunthala Engineering College, Avadi – Chennai.

Portfolio

https://www.hackerrank.com/mune eb_rahman

The https://muneeb-rahman-m.github.io/portfolio/

Description

Webpage contains game named as Space Shooters under Apps menu which is present in android mobile look a-like design. User needs to unlock the web mobile using mouse by click and

drag the lock icon in screen towards right until it overlaps with unlock icon. Once overlapped, it's unlocked. Click menu located in bottom right of the mobile screen.

Click game icon in screen then click on play button. Voila! Game has started. Game is played using **keyboard**. Enjoy!!... ©

Personal Details

Date of birth : 12-Sep-1988

Gender : Male

Nationality : Indian

Languages : English, Urdu and

Tamil

Marital status : Married

Awards

Monthly Summit award

Appreciation for exemplary commitment and collaboration with team to complete sprint deliverable's consistently.